<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Il mio blog</title><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/</id><updated>2025-04-22T12:00:00+02:00</updated><subtitle>A blog about everything and nothing</subtitle><entry><title>Guardians of the Mist: Uganda's Mountain Gorilla Conservation Success</title><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/2025/04/22/uganda-mountain-gorillas/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-22T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-04-22T12:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Plasma</name></author><id>tag:ale-pedroni.github.io,2025-04-22:/2025/04/22/uganda-mountain-gorillas/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How Uganda became a global success story in protecting one of the world's most endangered primates&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;TITOLONE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep in Uganda's misty forests of Bwindi Impenetrable National Park and Mgahinga Gorilla National Park lives one of the world's most endangered mammals—the mountain gorilla. With fewer than 1,100 individuals remaining worldwide, over half reside in the Uganda-Rwanda-Congo border region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uganda's conservation journey is particularly remarkable. In the 1980s, mountain gorilla populations had plummeted to dangerous lows due to poaching and habitat loss. The establishment of protected areas and innovative community-based conservation initiatives helped reverse this decline. Today, Uganda is one of only three countries where these magnificent primates can be seen in their natural habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gorilla tracking permit system created by Uganda Wildlife Authority represents an ingenious approach to conservation—tourism directly funds protection efforts while creating jobs for former poachers as trackers and guides. Communities surrounding the parks receive a percentage of permit revenues, giving them economic incentives to protect rather than exploit the forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has yielded impressive results: mountain gorilla numbers have grown from approximately 620 individuals in 1989 to over 1,000 today—one of the few great ape populations actually increasing rather than declining. Uganda's mountain gorilla conservation program stands as a testament to what's possible when economic development and wildlife protection work in harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Wildlife"></category><category term="gorillas"></category><category term="conservation"></category><category term="bwindi"></category><category term="tourism"></category></entry><entry><title>Uganda's Path to Independence: A Nation Reborn</title><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/2025/04/22/uganda-independence/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-22T11:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-04-22T11:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Your Name</name></author><id>tag:ale-pedroni.github.io,2025-04-22:/2025/04/22/uganda-independence/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The journey and key events that led to Uganda's independence from British colonial rule&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On October 9, 1962, Uganda emerged as an independent nation after decades under British colonial rule. Unlike many African independence movements, Uganda's transition was relatively peaceful, achieved primarily through negotiation rather than armed struggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road to self-governance began in earnest after World War II, with the formation of political parties like the Uganda National Congress in 1952. Milton Obote, who would become the country's first Prime Minister, rose to prominence by uniting various regional interests under the Uganda People's Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A unique feature of Uganda's independence arrangement was the preservation of traditional kingdoms within a federal structure. The Kabaka (king) of Buganda, Sir Edward Mutesa II, was appointed as the first President in a compromise that balanced modern democratic governance with traditional authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independence celebrations in Kampala were marked by the lowering of the Union Jack and raising of Uganda's new black, yellow, and red flag—colors representing the people, sunshine, and brotherhood. The nation embarked on its self-governance journey with optimism, though subsequent decades would bring both triumphs and significant challenges to this East African nation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="History"></category><category term="independence"></category><category term="colonialism"></category><category term="obote"></category><category term="britain"></category></entry><entry><title>Discovering the Source of the Nile: Uganda's Historic Claim to Fame</title><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/2025/04/22/source-of-nile/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-22T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-04-22T10:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Your Name</name></author><id>tag:ale-pedroni.github.io,2025-04-22:/2025/04/22/source-of-nile/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How the quest to find the source of the world's longest river led explorers to Uganda&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 1862, British explorer John Hanning Speke made a discovery that would end centuries of speculation and debate: he identified Lake Victoria in Uganda as the primary source of the Nile River. This revelation solved one of geography's greatest mysteries that had puzzled minds since the time of ancient Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing at Ripon Falls near Jinja (now submerged beneath the Owen Falls Dam), Speke declared he had found the long-sought "source of the Nile." This announcement wasn't without controversy, as his fellow explorer Richard Burton disagreed with his conclusion. Their public disagreement led to one of the most famous debates in the history of exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Jinja proudly calls itself the "Adventure Capital of East Africa," offering white-water rafting and other activities at what is recognized as the point where the world's longest river begins its 4,132-mile journey to the Mediterranean Sea. A monument near the source commemorates Speke's historic discovery, marking Uganda's special place in the story of one of humanity's oldest geographical quests.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="History"></category><category term="nile"></category><category term="exploration"></category><category term="speke"></category><category term="geography"></category></entry><entry><title>Welcome to the Brutalist Uganda-Inspired Site</title><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/2025/04/21/welcome-to-brutalist-site/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-21T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-04-21T10:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Plasma</name></author><id>tag:ale-pedroni.github.io,2025-04-21:/2025/04/21/welcome-to-brutalist-site/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An introduction to this brutalist website with a Ugandan flag-inspired color palette.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to Our Brutalist Website&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sample article that demonstrates the styling of our brutalist website, inspired by the colors of the Ugandan flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Brutalism in Web Design?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brutalism in web design is characterized by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raw, unpolished aesthetics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposed structure and functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bold typography and high contrast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal styling and animations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rejection of conventional design principles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brutalist websites prioritize content over aesthetic appeal, embracing a raw and unfiltered approach to design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Ugandan Flag Color Palette&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ugandan flag consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black&lt;/strong&gt; (#000000): Representing the African people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yellow/Gold&lt;/strong&gt; (#FCDC04): Symbolizing sunshine and vitality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red&lt;/strong&gt; (#D90000): Representing brotherhood and the blood that unites all Africans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've extended this palette with additional colors that complement the flag's vibrant scheme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep Maroon&lt;/strong&gt; (#8C0303): A darker shade of the flag's red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light Gold&lt;/strong&gt; (#FFE866): A lighter version of the flag's yellow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark Charcoal&lt;/strong&gt; (#333333): A softer black for text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Off-White&lt;/strong&gt; (#F5F5F5): For backgrounds and contrast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forest Green&lt;/strong&gt; (#006633): Representing Uganda's lush landscapes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a simple Python function that generates the colors of the Ugandan flag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;ugandan_flag_colors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sd"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Return the primary colors of the Ugandan flag.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;colors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;black&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;#000000&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;yellow&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;#FCDC04&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;#D90000&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;colors&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Get the colors&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;flag_colors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ugandan_flag_colors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sa"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;The colors of the Ugandan flag are: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;flag_colors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;keys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="si"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Blockquote Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brutalism in web design is not about being ugly on purpose. It's about being honest, direct, and functional. It strips away unnecessary decoration to focus on the content and structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lists Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reasons to Use Brutalist Design:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authenticity&lt;/strong&gt;: Raw and unfiltered design language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on Content&lt;/strong&gt;: Minimal distractions from what matters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;: Fewer design elements means faster loading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memorability&lt;/strong&gt;: Stands out in a sea of polished websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Honesty&lt;/strong&gt;: Represents digital interfaces as they truly are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brutalist Principles:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expose functionality and structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use raw, unpolished elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employ high contrast and bold typography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid unnecessary decoration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge conventional design expectations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brutalist theme inspired by the Ugandan flag colors offers a unique, bold, and memorable design that prioritizes content while paying homage to the vibrant colors of Uganda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to explore the rest of the site to see how different elements are styled within this brutalist framework.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Design"></category><category term="brutalism"></category><category term="design"></category><category term="uganda"></category></entry></feed>