<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Il mio blog - Wildlife</title><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/feeds/wildlife.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/</id><updated>2025-04-22T12:00:00+02:00</updated><subtitle>A blog about everything and nothing</subtitle><entry><title>Guardians of the Mist: Uganda's Mountain Gorilla Conservation Success</title><link href="https://Ale-Pedroni.github.io/2025/04/22/uganda-mountain-gorillas/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-04-22T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-04-22T12:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Plasma</name></author><id>tag:ale-pedroni.github.io,2025-04-22:/2025/04/22/uganda-mountain-gorillas/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How Uganda became a global success story in protecting one of the world's most endangered primates&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;TITOLONE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep in Uganda's misty forests of Bwindi Impenetrable National Park and Mgahinga Gorilla National Park lives one of the world's most endangered mammals—the mountain gorilla. With fewer than 1,100 individuals remaining worldwide, over half reside in the Uganda-Rwanda-Congo border region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uganda's conservation journey is particularly remarkable. In the 1980s, mountain gorilla populations had plummeted to dangerous lows due to poaching and habitat loss. The establishment of protected areas and innovative community-based conservation initiatives helped reverse this decline. Today, Uganda is one of only three countries where these magnificent primates can be seen in their natural habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gorilla tracking permit system created by Uganda Wildlife Authority represents an ingenious approach to conservation—tourism directly funds protection efforts while creating jobs for former poachers as trackers and guides. Communities surrounding the parks receive a percentage of permit revenues, giving them economic incentives to protect rather than exploit the forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has yielded impressive results: mountain gorilla numbers have grown from approximately 620 individuals in 1989 to over 1,000 today—one of the few great ape populations actually increasing rather than declining. Uganda's mountain gorilla conservation program stands as a testament to what's possible when economic development and wildlife protection work in harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Wildlife"></category><category term="gorillas"></category><category term="conservation"></category><category term="bwindi"></category><category term="tourism"></category></entry></feed>